Take care of her.
Driver, please stop near
the Hotel Akbar International.
Look through all the papers in here
and put them over there.
Is this your house?
-Yes, it’s my house.
-Your name?
Have you got any ID?
Yes, I have my passporl.
I’m from India.
Look under the bed.
Give those pictures to me.
Did you get the taxi for Daniel Pearl?
-Yes, sir.
-Where did you get the taxi from?
Sir, from Two Swords.
Get out.
What’s your name?
Hello, son.
-You didn’t see anyone at 7 pm?
-No.
There was no foreigner here yesterday?
Yesterday evening,
did you see a foreigner here?
No, sir.
Hello, Paracha, this is Masud.
He had short hair, skinny
and was wearing glasses.
We found one person.
-What is your name?
-Aqeel Nawaz.
We’ve brought you something.
It was the best we could find in Karachi.
If you need anything, don’t hesitate.
Goodbye, Mariane, be brave.
Come on, get them in the car.
Go on, move it.
Make sure nothing goes wrong.
We’re conducting
a proper investigation.
How long have you been here?
One year, sir.
How many children do you have?
Sir, only one child.
-Only one?
-Yes.
The ISI came to my parents and asked,
where did this girl come from?
From India?
I know that but...
Connect those lines.
How many lines are you getting us?
Six lines.
Where are they coming from?
We’re cutting off
the neighbors’ phone lines.
What will happen to their phones?
They’ll have to use yours.
Check everybody’s ID
before you let them through.
Have you seen this person?
I’m looking for somebody who
stayed here called Chaudhry Bashir.
Here is his number.
How long do we have to stay here?
Until we find him.
Okay, we’re on our way.
Masud, where’s the coach station
for Muzaffarabad?
Is Arif going to Muzaffarabad?
From Pirwadhi Bus Station?
Is Arif here?
Where is Hashim’s house?
Where is Hashim?
We want to search the house.
Why are you all coming in here?
Come on, help us push.
What do you think of this, Shabir?
What’s your name?
Is this computer yours?
-This computer is mine.
-Turn it on, please.
It can’t be switched on
because the hard disk has crashed.
What happened to the hard disk?
There was a virus on it and it crashed.
I took jito repair two days ago.
-It broke down two days ago?
-Yes.
Okay.
Take him in.
How many computers
have you connected in that building?
In that building, twenty or more.
-Twenty?
-Yes.
Is this your job?
Yes, this is what I do.
We are looking
for Daniel Pearl’s photograph.
We have new software
that can recover deleted files
from your hard drive
just like that.
Whatever you know, just tell us now.
You won’t have any difficulties.
If the Americans find out,
you’ll be in big trouble
and we won’t be able to help you.
There was no-one else?
You did it on your own?
No, sir,
my cousin Suleiman was with me.
-Okay, he’s your cousin?
-Yes.
Where does he live?
-He lives in Karachi.
-Is he in Karachi now?
-Yes.
-Come on, let’s go.
Well done.
Quickly, quickly.
This is the place.
There he is.
That’s him.
Yes, he’s the one.
Come on, move it.
Get out of the way.
Give me his phone.
Tell him what I told you to say.
It’s Suleiman.
-He says he’s not there.
-Do you have his cell number?
-Yes.
-Then let’s try it.
Be quiet.
Suleiman speaking.
-What do you want?
-I need to speak to you.
I need to meet you urgently.
Not now. We’ll meet up early
tomorrow morning and talk. Okay?
Sir, he’s saying we’ll speak tomorrow.
Take down this number.
Open the door.
Sir, this is the phone company.
We don’t have any time, you bastard.
We need to trace a number.
Sorry, sir, the office is closed, we can’t
give you any information right now.
What do you need
to do with this number?
I am CID Chief Javed Habib.
You know what I can do?
Screw your confidentiality,
I need that information.
A man has been kidnapped, a foreigner.
If something happens to him,
Pakistan will have a bad reputation.
-Who’s there?
-Don’t move.
-Put your hands up.
-Take him away.
You’ll be sorry.
God is great.
Where is Daniel Pearl?
I don’t know.
What do you know?
I don’t know anything.
Tell me whatever you know.
What do you know?
Just tell me.
What did you do?
I don’t know anything.
-What do you know?
-Nothing.
Who asked you to e-mail?
Who are you working for?
Sheikh Omar.
Quickly, come on.
Check all the rooms.
Search everything.
Who are you people?
Is this the way to come into
respectable people’s homes?
Where’s Sheikh Omar?
You must have a contact number.
Where is Sheikh Omar?
-We don’t know anything.
-Give me Adil’s phone.
Give me Adil’s phone.
Omar Sheikh?
Yes?
It’s Javed Habib speaking,
Omar Sheikh.
We have all the information,
we know everything about you.
Farhad, Adil, Suleiman,
we have all of them.
Check your caller ID.
Come on, bring them out.
As far as I know
he is not alive.
On February 5th,
I spoke to my brothers on the phone
and I told them
to take the patient to the doctor’s.
This was a code to release the hostage.
I would let you speak to her,
but she doesn’t speak Urdu.
Okay?
I’m here, Mariane.
Have you no decency?
It’s crazy, they’re everywhere.
Oh, my daughter.
You are so beautiful.
The aim of Buddhism
is to draw out all the strength,
courage, wisdom and goodwill.