Is anybody there?
Jeanne.
I’m always happytoseeyou, but to
keep coming twice, three times a day—
- I need to confess.
-You already confessed this morning.
I need to confess again.
What terrible sin
haveyou committed since then...
that can’t wait till tomorrow
to be forgiven?
I saw a poor monk without shoes,
so I gave him some.
There’s no sin ¡n chanty,Jeanne.
- They weren’t my shoes.
- Whose were they?
- My father’s.
- I’m sure he’ll forgive you.
He already did.
But I wantJesus
to forgive me tcx.
If we were to ask forgiveness
all the time...
we’d spend our whole life
¡n church.
- Is that bad?
-Well, no, but—
-Areyou happy at home?
- Oh, yes, very.
And your mother?
Everything’s fine with her?
Yes, she’s wonderñil.
And your sister, Cathen ne,
she’s still your best friend?
My sisters just—
She’s wonderftil.
And what atxut your other friends?
You don’t like playing with them?
Oh, yes.
I play with them, lots.
Everything sounds wonderftil.
Yes, it is.
Then why are you here so often?
I feel safe here.
It’s where I can talk to him.
Him?
Well, I tryto talkto him...
but mostly he’s the one
who does the talking.
Who ¡s this The’?
He neyer says his name.
What does he...
look like?
Beautiful.
And what does he say to you?
He says—
He says I must be gcxxi..
and help everyone
and take care of myself.
Do you think he’s coming
from the sky?
Perhaps.
But wherever he’s coming from,
I think you should listen to him...
cause ¡t sounds like
he’s giving you very gcxxi advice.
It’s—
It’s wonderñil!
It’s wonderfiji.
Jeanne.
We’ve all been lcxking for you.
The English are everywhere.
- I was ¡n the church.
- Really?
I was talking to the priest
Do you know what he said to me?
Bum over there!
Tell me later.
Quick, hide ¡n here.
- Where are you gonna be?
- I’ll be right here.
I promise.
Well, that’s what I call Lxxty.
Comrade.
Awoman with a sword.
If that’s Gcxfs will,
then so be it.
Fine with me.
I love women.
Hold still, bitch.
How can Ido it
¡fyou keep wnggling atxut?
Your turn now.
Gcxi, preserve and bless the soul
of this, our dearly departed.
Keep us safe from fear and sin.
Amen.
Come on.
Listen, J eanne.
Your aunt and uncle are gonna take you
to their house for a couple of weeks...
You understand?
Lord, we give thanks
for the fcxxi youve given us.
Teach us always
to love this land...
and to save ¡t from those
who seek to destroy ¡t.
-Amen.
So, goxi night, then.
- What’s going to happen to her?
-She’ll be fine.
She’ll grow up, find a gcxx man,
make him some children. Don’t worry.
She’s been hurt, but she’ll survive.
Tomorrow she’ll be
as right as rain.
You’ll see.
Iwanttoseea priest
-Whydid she have to die?
- Only GcxJ can answer that.
I knowJesus says
to Ioveyour enemies, but I can’t
I just want the English
to bum in hell forever and ever!
I realize your angerjeanne.
But we must learn to forgive.
It’s hard...
but revenge will never
bring axut ace.
Whatwill?
And what will bring her back?
And whydid she have to die
¡n the first place instead of me?
Why didn’t He take my life
instead of hers?
It was my fault!
Iwas late!
She gave me
Whydid
her hiding place!
He save me?
Calm down,Jeanne.
Calnm diin.
I don’t pretend
to know God’s will...
but one thing I am sure:
The Lord always has a gcxxi reason.
Perhaps He chose you because
He needs you...
for some higher calling.
As long as you answer that call...
your sisterwill not
have died in vain.
I don’twanttowait
for His call.
Be patient
I want to be with Him always.
Soonyou will be able to take part
in your Holy Mass.
When you eat of His flesh
and dnnk of His blood...
you will be at onewith Him.
I want to be at one with Him now.
So, what did he say?
He says we must bring her to church
whenever she wants.
Easy for him. He’s not the one
who has to do the bringing.
Come on.
This ¡s ¡mportant.
We mustn’t let her out of our sight
Don’t worry. I will watch her
like my own shadow.
I want to be at one with You now.
A message for the dauphin of France.
A message.
Captain, a message for the dauphin.
III take ¡t.
The dauphin!
Louis. Louis. Hey.
Shouldn’t you be learning your lessons?
I don’t want to learn.
Iwant to fight.
You will. But for nowyou must
at least learn towipeyour nose.
A letter for His Majesty.
Another one from this girl
calling herself the Maiden of Lorraine.
I can read for myself,
you know?
She pretends she’s been sent by God.
Charlatans.
It’s a pity there isn’t enough wcxxi
to bum them all.
- She says she’ll be here tomorrow.
- You mustn’t see her, My Lord.
What difference does it make
where she comes from?
If she comes from Burgundy,
¡t makes a difference.
It might be a trap.
Lcxk, signed X
What sort of a name ¡s X’?
Or must we assume that a messenger
of God can’t even write her own name?
My Lord, Trémoille ¡s correct.
She says she hears voices.
She may be a sorceress,
a witch.
Regnault, you see witches everywhere.
She’s just a peasant
A peasant who cares about her king.
All she wants ¡s to see me crowned
and permission to fight for me.
Not exactly. She wants you
to give her an army at your expense.
Bearing ¡n mind your mother stole every
last piece of gold ¡n the treasury...
I fail to see how you can afford
such an adventure.
I can see heriflwantto.
You mustn’t see her,
Your Majesty.
She may be an ¡nstrument
of the devil.
Well, I thinkyou should.
Well, here’s an amusing situation.
I would lcwe to know why my devoted
mother-in-law thinks one thing...
and my two most loyal
and trusted advisors...
think precisely the opxsite.
Because I care atxut you.
Come here.
Your health and happiness has always
been my first concern, Charles...
You think so, eh?
I know, for exam pl e,
the sickness that plagues your heart
I knowhowpainfulitis
for you to have loved a father...
without ever knowing
if he was reallyyours.
Do I know you enough? Hmm?
What has that got to do
with this maiden?
Who better than a messenger from Gcxi
to give answers to your questions?
You think she was sent from God?
You’re a fine judge
of character, Charles.
Itil take you less than five minutes
to exse her if she’s a fake.
But ¡f she’s noL
then she will giveyou
your answers...
and place the crown on your head.
With respect to my lady, I think it’s
going to take more than a peasant girl—
I’m not interested
¡n what you think, Trémoille...
simple people up and down this country
are already talking axut her.
Now you know
what simple people are like--
always ready to believe
any old prophecy.
Like this one...
axut a virgin from Lorraine...
saving France.
And now...
this girl comes along...
from Lorraine.
And suddenly, there’s a spark
of hope ¡n their simple minds.
You shouldn’t disappoint them.
If they believe ¡n her—
¡f she can put back
the fire ¡n ourarmy—
then I believe ¡n her too.
R
Louis, be quiet for once.
- She’s coming, Your Majesty.
-All right.
Calm yourself.
Your Majesty, I urge you
not to see this woman.
It all reeks oía Burgundian trap.
My astrologers assure me the timing
is propitious: Leo with Virgo rising.
Have you never noticed
on the astrological chart..
that the virgin
is next to the lion?
Supposing she’s an assassin?
My-My-My dear Trémoille...
I’m not even kingyet.
Who would want to assassinate me?
She’s arrived, My Lord.
She’s ¡n the guards’ rm.
Fine, fine.
I supxse I shall have
to make a decision.
Why ¡s life so complicated?
Sometimes I really wish
I could be someone else.
That’s a gxxi idea, sire.
What doyou mean?
Let someone else
pretend to be you.
And see ¡f she can find me?
That’s a brilliant idea.
Who wants to be king?
Alençon, my noble duke.
My royal cousin.
So fine, so brave, so rich.
Gules de Rais.
Marshall of France.
You would be perfect
to sit on mythrone.
So perfect that you might
like it t much...
and therefore disturb
my-my fragile ace of mind.
La Hire.
My angry captain,
and bravest in France.
Scarred bya dozen wars, butwith
a heart and a stomach for a dozen more.
-You could pass for the king.
- Damn bloody right I could.
Until you open your mouth,
because no one...
with a tongue like that
could Fxssible pass as king of France.
It looks like it shall have
to be me after all.
The only man
who’s poorer than I am...
therefore the only man
I can trust.
Dignified, honorable, wise.
What more can we ask oía king?
My lord, I’m not sure that—
Are you not prepared
to die foryour king?
- Of course I am.
- G.
Until then, feel free to live
like a king. Bring her up.
Sireyou know how bad lam
at this sort of game.
Pretend it’s not a game.
Make way for the dauphin.
- Mother?
- Not now.
I have come to see the dauphin.
Who are you?
His most gracious majesty,
Charles de Valois...
dauphin of France.
I can see you are a gcxxi man.
But you’re not the dauphin.
I’m sorry to insist,
but I must see the dauphin.
We have no time to lose.
Where is he?
He’s here.
Find him yourself.
There’s no need to be afraid, sire.
I’m not the king.
I knowyou’renotyet,
butyou will bescxn.
Out. Out.
How didyou knowwho lam?
- Her voices, of course.
- That’s him, they said.
‘The one ¡n the comer
with the big nose.’
Back offi
Oh, my gentle dauphin.
I have a message...
from the King of Heaven...
foryou.
You only.
Follow me.
Your Majesty, I really think—
My dear loyal Trémoille,
I know I can count on you...
to-to ensure our privacy.
I need to talk to her alone.
He needs to talk to her alone.
Fine.
I was ax,ut ten years old.
It was a beautiftil spring day.
I was taking a shortcut home
through the forest..
when a strange wind...
began to blow.
It was such a strange soun4
almost ilke wojT..
calling me.
The second time...
was manyyears later.
I was coming back from church,
when suddenly...
the same...
violent wind.
Then...
a shape..
appeared..
in the middle of the sky.
The shape...
of a man.
Everything was moving so fast.
So fast.
The wind, the clouds.
I couldn’t move.
I couldn’t breathe.
I was so frightened.
He was...
here.
But Idid not understand
what it was He wanted me to do.
What was my mission?
What could I do to help my country?
But how? I was nothing.
I was justa pcorgirl.
I did not know anything atxut—
axut making war or riding.
Sol decided towait...
and not to speak of it
to anybody.
You did well.
I didn’t wait long.
I was going to Mass,
like I do every day...
and the same...
strange wind—
Everything was made clear.
GcxJ had given me a message.
A message to deliver.
What—
What was the message?
He said...
that I must save France
from her enemies...
and bring her back
into the hands of God.
And He told me that I...
will lead you
to the altar at Reims...
where you will be crowned...
the king...
of France.
- Sire, are you—
- I’m fine.
This is, in fact,Jean d’Aulon,
my loyal friend and finest archer.
I put her ¡n your care.
and guard herwithyour life.
Sire, I won’t be needing any Icxigings
¡f we’re to be marching on Orléans.
Orleans has held out
fôr six months...
so I don’t supse a few days more
will make much difference.
Take some rest.
Put the bags here.
Please accept my apologies...
for me pretending
to be the—you know.
Do you think
that I can have some water?
Water. Yes, of course.
Would you get some water?
-Anything else?
-l needtoseea priest.
- Now?
- Yes. I didn’t confess today.
All right
Raymond, a priest.
Anything else?
I shall alsobe needing
a new war horse...
a sword, armor...
-Now?
- Better today than tomorrow.
This might take a little time...
but let me see what I can do.
Oh! I shall also be needing someone
who can read and write.
This Ican do.
I was studying at the University
of Pans until the English invaded it.
- I thought you were an archer.
-Yes, lam.
The king of England.
I want to give him the chance
to leave in peace...
before I get to Orléans.
The’ archbishop andi hai.tjust begun
negotiat/oiis with the 8urgundians
If we can bring them over
to our side—
Negotiate, by all means,
but from a position of strength.
If the English take Orleans,
there’ll be nothing left to negotiate.
The rest of the country
will be theirs.
My lady, ¡twill be
the height of folly...
to let this child
lead our army...
¡n the kings name
without verifying her true motives.
My Lord, Trémoille ¡s right
We must be absolutely certain that
she ¡s not an instrument of the devil.
How can anyone be
absolutely certain axut anything?
Sometimes, our intuitions
are our best counselors.
We must listen to Mother Holy Church
before we listen to our intuitions.
Wait.
She claims to be a virgin.
Well, that’s something
we can examine...
and be absolutely certain atxut
Let’s find out.
What ¡f she’s not?
If she’s not,
I’ll kill her myself.
There is nosign
of corruption or violation.
She ¡s ¡ntact
And what, exactly,
was this vision wearing?
I don’t remember.
This vision,
did it give you anything?
An object?
A ring ora rosary...
or anything bywhich
we can venfýyour claim?
He gave me gcxd advice.
During your childhcxxi, did you have
any sort of military experience?
Are you practiced ¡n the skills
of swordsmanship?
No, but I’m gocxi with a stick.
Doyou know what
a Dijon Culvenn is?
It’s an item of artillery.
How can you expect
to raise the siege of Orléans...
¡f you’re ignorant
axut mcxiem artillery?
The road to Orléans is long,
and I have gcxxi captains with me.
Iwill learn fast believe me.
Wewould like to believeyou,Jeanne,
but we feel...
that ¡f GcxJ wanted us
to believe you...
he would’ve sent a sign with you.
So, can you do something?
Show us something?
A sign to prove...
that you are sent by GcxJ.
I did not come here
to perform tricks.
You are all much cleverer
than I am.
I mean, me,
I dont know A from B.’
yet you do not see His hand
in having guided me...
through 500 leagues of enemy country
to bnng you His help.
Is that not prcxf enough?
Or do you still need more signs?
Give me an army.
Take me to Orléans.
And there you will see the sign
that I was sent to make.
Dunois.
- What?
- A big one, straight at us.
What side?
What?
I have wonderful news, finally.
He is sending her to us.
Thanks be to God. We’re saved.
It’s—
It’s wonderñil.
Calm yourself, Xaintrailles.
Who has finally done what?
The dauphin. He’s sending us
fcxxi and supplies and an army...
led byjeanne,
the maiden from Lorraine.
Isn’t ¡t wonderful?
Yes, it’s a miracle.
I can’t believe
they are sending a woman.
I wonder what color dress
she’ll beweanng.
Yes, we were.
- Where are the English?
- Everywhere. Where’s the fcxxi?
It’s coming.
I rode on ahead.
I have a message
for the captain of the English army.
- His name ¡s TaILxt.
-Iknow.
- Canyou take me to him?
- He’s on the other side of the river.
So, who gave the order for me
to be brought to this side of the river?
Hey, my friend. It’s gcxxi
to see your ugly damn face again.
- La Hire, I’m warning you. Don’t swear.
- Sorry,Jeanne.
Let me ¡ntrcxiuce the king’s
half-brother, the dogged Lord Dunois.
Lord Dunois, will you show me
to the other side of the river?
Wait. Waili
Fine! Go now, ¡fyou want!
But not with me!
You may have a dutyto God,
but I have a duty to my people.
And my people are starving.
Right now, rm going to take
the fcxxi back to the city.
And ¡fyou can please calm down
and let me accompanyyou to Orleans...
twill bemyhonor
to welcome you.
Jesus Christ
The goddamn English
will pay for this.
Yes, theywill, and so will you
if you don’t stop swearing.
Come on. rm happy
towelcomeyou ¡n my tavern.
Come on ¡n.
La Hire, Gules,
let me show you something.
Tourelles are around here.
The river crosses there.
Calm down.
You can’t blame those people.
They’ve been hearing
axut you for weeks.
There’s nothing to hear!
And why is there nothing to hear?
Because I haven’t done anything!
And why haven’t I?
‘Cause none of you
will listen to me!
Why don’tyou join us?
We’re atxut to discuss
the campaign.
I’m sorry.
So from here,
Taftxt has spread his forces...
between these forts up here.
But ¡n the last few days ¡t seems,
according to our scouts...
that some trps have been
deployed to this fort here.
What axut this huge pile down here?
That’s the Tourelles.
The English were planning...
to launch an attack from ¡t,
but then we broke down the bridge--
And what doesJeanne think?
I don’t think.
I leave that to God.
lam nothing in all of this.
Im just the messenger.
SOrn
what ¡s the message?
We give the English...
a last chance
to go home ¡n ace.
And ¡f they reftise?
If they reftise...
we recross the river...
and attack here...
at the Tourelles.
That makes no sense at all.
The Tourelles ¡s virtually impregnable.
If we are on the other side of the river
attacking the Tourelles...
what’s to stop TaItxt
attacking the city from the north?
-God.
- God. Why, of course.
We’d forgotten atxut Him.
but by tomorrow night,
some of you will be dead.
With
attack
respect, we can’t just
the Tourelles like that.
- It’s a very complicated matter.
- What’s so complicated axut it?
All you have to do ¡s what you’re told.
What could be simpler than that?
lam the drum...
on which Gcxi is beating out
His message.
He’s beating ¡t so hard,
it’s bursting my ears!
I mean, for our pride
to suddenly be usurped by--
Well, with all due respect,
bya-
bya girl.
So that’s ¡t.
To you, Im just a girl.
Putyourselfin my shoes fora moment
How would you feel ¡fyou were me?
Knowing what I know...
enormous gratitude.
One hell of a girl. huh?
I warned you.
I do love her when
gets well and truly
herfire
stoked.
Me too.
Hello, my friends!
What a journey.
But we made ¡t.
Back together again.
Let’s have some fun.
Fine.
I shall look like a man.
R
How dare you stop me
from doing God’s will!
He didn’t tell you
to cut all your hairoffi
How dare you tell me
what God tells me to do!
Whatever! But since He’s not going
to come down and cut it Himself--
At least let someone
cut ¡t properly!
Raymond, bring the scissors.
Louis, fetch the mirror.
Stop getting so angry aLxut everything.
Calm down.
lam calm!
It’s GcxJ that’s angry.
I need to send a letter, now.
Fine.
“Tow,i Heniy, king of England ..
and to jvu, Duke ofßeth’bnl
who call jvurself regent of France...
obey the King of Hean
and abandon vur siege.
Gi back the ke
to the other towns yoiñe taken..
and go back home
to)vur island
To)VLŠ L &d Ta/hot, I &gu
as humb/yas I can beg you ..
fi the sake of the I/its
ofycur soldiers..
do not biing about
your own destruction.
Message
Wßut if)vu dO flOt
heed my warning...
then wi? shall raise
such a battle ciy...
as there has not been heard in France
/bra thousandyears W
Sire, message.
“This is the third and last time
I will write to)vu
Ifyou are still here at noor
I warn JOU..
you vAil hear from me
to yo ur vely great destruction
Please give me your answer
speedylyw
Go fuckyourselfi
What did they say?
They said
they’ll think axut ¡t.
Good.
To be honest,
I don’t think they’ll leave tomorrow.
I can’t wait for tomorrow.
French blcxxi is spilling.
Wake up! Hurry!
They’ve started the battle
without me.
There’s a battle to fight
and awarto bewon.
Damn.
Sound the retreat!
My banner.
My banner!
Open the gate!
What happened?
Who gave the order to attack?
Gxi knows.
It was a bad idea.
Were the men confessed?
Where are the priests?
We didn’t take them.
We wanted to make a surprise attack.
Dunois, was it you
who gave the order to attack?
- Answer me!
- Can we discuss this later?
Sooner ¡s better than later.
Wait!
You’ll be killed!
Follow me!
Follow me
and I will giveyouvictory
Close it!
Close the drawbridge!
To the drawbridge!
- What ¡s she doing?
- To the drawbridge!
- The drawbridge ¡s closed.
- Not for long.
Let’s go!
It’s a great victory—
yourvictory—
but we must follow ¡t through
and pursue the English...
back to Taftxt’s camp unless,
of course, you have another gcxd idea.
First, we find
the biggest army we can.
- Then we return to Orléans.
-The bridge has been pulled down.
-The English are rebuilding ¡t.
- And how do you know?
You have been with your counsel,
and I have been with mine.
Becareful with mybaby.
- That’s the Tourelles.
- Wonderful.
Captain!
Lcxks like the froggy whore’s
coming to pay us a visit.
I’d better tell Glasdale.
Let’s put the horses over there.
Fathers, please, bless them.
- Please, bless them all.
-Wewill.
Let’s plan this attack a little more
carefully than this morning.
Good idea.
We’ve got, uh, visitors.
Glasdale!
Doyou hear me?
You, who call me a whore...
I feel pity foryou,
for your soul...
and for the souls of your men!
Yield! Yield now
to the King of Heaven!
Or go back to your island!
And you, go back to your pigsty!
Man the walls.
This morning...
GcxJ gave usa great victory.
But ¡t ¡s nothing compared
towhat Heis readytogiveus now.
I knowyouareall
tired and hungry...
but I swear toyou...
that even ¡f these English were hanging
from the clouds by their fingertips...
we would pull them down
before nightfall.
Now...
let all those who love me...
follow me!
Follow me!
You were saying?
Come on!
-1go nght.
-1go left!
Come on!
Get that flicking pot of oil
up here now!
Get that flicking thing moving!
You’re beautiful.
Let’s see ¡f you’re powerful.
- Do something!
- Like what?
I don’t care!
Do something!
And fire!
Fire!
What the flick?
Txhigh.
Reload!
- Get out of here!
-Where are the men?
You’re gonna get killed!
Get out of her&
Come on, fight!
Go!
Bring the culvenn!
Get ouU
I’m going up the side!
-Jeanne!
- Leave me alone!
Hurry!
Come on! Come on!
Yes!
Hey, you just killed mywoman!
Captain!
Go to hell.
Call the physician!
The physician!
Damn it!
Louis, find the physician.
We have to take out the arrow.
There must be something we can do
for her, for Christ’s sakes.
-Yes. You can pray.
-Good idea.
I swear that I will
never swearagain in my life...
¡f You save her life.
But I’m warning You,
if You let her die...
then You’re the biggest—
- Don’t swear.
- He heard me.
Why aren’t you fighting?
You’ve been badly wounded.
- It’s nothing. It’s—
— It’s an arrow.
And it’s ¡n deep.
You must staystill
till the physician arrives.
Physicians are a waste of time.
We’ll have more luck with this charm.
It saved my life at Agincourt
I’d rather die than use magic.
You will die ¡f that arrow
stays ¡n you much longer.
Well, at least this
won’t txther us anymore.
Now, let’s go to the battle!
Please!
She’s nuts.
You must staycaim.
You must rest.
I’ll rest.
But you have to...
promise me...
that you’ll-
that you’ll go back to the battle.
I promise.
Hurry!
QuickJy
Do something!
She’s sleeping.
What?
Come on back!
Why areyou running away?
- We have to press on the attack.
- Sound the retreat.
- I promised Jeanne we’d fight on.
- I made no such promise.
- Sound the retreat for the night.
- No, that was her order.
I’m fed up
with taking her orders!
She swore she’d defeat
the English before nightfall!
Instead, she goes and plays the fcxl,
gets herself nearly killed!
Lcxk!
Look at the mess we’re ¡n!
We are worse off
than ¡f she’d never come at all.
Now do as Isay
and sound the retreat!
Where are you going?
Hey, come back!
Come back and fight!
-What areyou making?
- A message for the English.
So, what are the men saying?
She’s a gift from God
Some even call her a saint.
- I’d gladly follow her through hell.
- Will you go that far ¡f she asks you?
Of course I will,
and I’ve been there before.
There’s one thing
I don’t quite understand.
She’s been sent to us by God.
Whydoes Heallow her
to be wounded so badly?
Maybe the gxxi question ¡s,
¡s she really sent byGcxi?
Who knows?
God knows.
Ooh.
Awoman with a sword.
You’ve hurt my feelings.
Frenchies!
What happened to your precious angel?
Huh?
Frenchies! Frenchies!
I’ll tell you what happened!
We sent the little bitch
back to hell...
so she can go flick
with the devil!
What are you gonna do now,
Frenchies?
Why not come out and fight?
Come on!
Bastards, wake up!
Or are you tc busy praying...
to bring your little flicking witch
back from the dead?
Doyou hear me?
I hearyou!
I’m alive!
May GcxJ forgive your blasphemy...
fôri neverwill.
I never will!
What are you doing?
You need to rest.
We must wake up the soldiers, now!
My fine soldiers, wake up!
To arms!
Wake up! Wake up!
We must fight the battle!
My fine soldiers,
the battle has begun!
Wakeup!
The time has come!
The battle has begun!
-To arms!
-Yes?
My soldiers, we need this tower up!
We need this tower up, now!
Pull!
- What’s going on?
- We’re taking back the Tourelles.
Get ready
Go wake up Glasdale.
- What are you doing?
- Sending a message to Glasdale.
- With that?
-Yes.
But you’ve got ¡t back-to-front
Listen, I know what I’m doing...
so either lend a hand
or get back to bed.
I’m going to send a message
to Glasdale t.
My lord?
What?
The French witch,
she’s back from the dead.
Hurry up, men!
Don’t you think we should take
some time to think about this?
Sooner ¡s better than later.
To arms!
Gxxi morning.
This one.
What the flick ¡s she playing at?
I don’t know! The question ¡s,
what ¡s she doing now?
How can we plan anything
¡f she doesn’t consult with us?
- Did we consult with her yesterday?
- Don’t even start
- You agreed to attack yesterday t.
- Yes, but that doesn’t count
- Why ¡s that?
- Because I always agree to attack.
To arms!
Crazy bitch.
She doesn’t even know
how to use it.
Oh, my God!
- Fuck! Close the dcxrs!
- Close the doors!
- Open the door!
- Load the xrcupine!
Pull!
And pull!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Never wait for miracles.
Stay there.
French whore!
Come and get me!
What are you waiting for?
Yes? Oh,Jeanne!
Find your archers
and bum that door!
Right away!
Push!
Prepare the gate!
Come on!
Position!
Fire!
Water!
Oh, my God!
Kill her.
Fuck. Reload!
More archers!
Perfect.
Help me!
Get your men!
We’ll load this up as a battering ram!
Already done.
- What?
- Nothing.
Help me with these men, please.
As you command.
Wait.
What are you doing?
We’re going to open that dxw.
Isn’t that what you want?
Get out of my flicking way!
Fill the cauldron!
Fucking French!
What the flick do you know axut me?
Reload.
Reload!
Fill the flicking cauldron!
What are you waiting for?
More men!
Pour the oil!
What are you doin& Jeanne?
I’m playing.
What are you doing
to mejeanne?
Doyou hear me?
Are you all right?
Cairim down.
It’s over.
We won.
-Wewon?
-Yes.
Fucking bitch.
My friend! My soldier!
In my arms.
-Wewon?
-Won?
No. No,Jeanne.
So small aword will neverdo.
This ¡s victory!
This is glory!
What’s the matter?
This is glory?
Doesn’t matter.
This ¡s not possible.
It ¡s not possible.
You Icxk disappointed.
Isn’t this what you wanted?
No.
Not like this.
For weeks you’ve been asking for this.
-What areyou doing?
- Nothing.
I’m just taking his teeth.
But you just can’t kill a man
for his teeth.
Why not? He has gcxxl teeth.
Because—
Because you can’t!
What about all this?
But that’s different
Not me.
He’s my pnsoner...
Ican take his teeth
¡fi want to.
No you Œn’t!
Stop it!
Here. Take this!
He’s mine now.
Here, you.
Bravo. And what ax,ut
all the other prisoners?
- Doweletthem gotcx?
- I don’t know.
Maybe.
We must confess.
Please, we have to be confessed.
All of us.
I know this is not normal custom...
but, uh—
Everything’s gonna be fine.
He’s gonna confess us.
Kneel. Kneel.
Alençon brings bad news.
Thousands of English are forming up
on the far side of the river.
I think we should count our men
and get ready.
Let’s go.
111go.
Alone.
I have a message foryour King Henry!
It ¡s a message from Gx!
Go home!
Ga naw, ¡n peace!
Ifyou do not go now,
you will be buried ¡n this field!
I’ve seen enough blood!
But ¡fyou want more...
I can’t stop you!
I can onlywamyou
that it will be your blcxxi..
not ours!
I’m waiting for your answer.
Never wait for miracles.
Stand by to attack.
Please.
My Lord...
Now that’s what I call
a goddamn blocdy miracle.
She was on her white horse alone...
facing the whole English army,
and she drove them away...
and now Orléans ¡s free.
We lost Orléans.
I want that girl.
I want that girl burned.
That’s meant to be a crown?
Don’t you have something more regal?
The English txk the real one.
It’s been muddy so long I forgot
how gcxxi ¡t Icxked cleaned up.
But did you remember to clean up
what’s inside as well?
I ask for a grandiose coronation,
and this ¡s what you give?
This whole thing is going to be
an utter fiasco!
You gave me 3 days to prepare.
Your fathers coronation took 3 months.
He’s right.
We should call for a delay.
No time.
We can’t hold up the ceremony.
No telling when the English
might come back.
Let them come. Let them see
who ¡s the true king of France.
Those damn English. We should be
doing this in Pans in Notre Dame.
It is much more prestigious
and twice as big.
It is the sacred place that matters,
not the size. Correct, Bishop?
Yes, my lady.
True kings of France must be anointed...
in our great cathedral of Reims
with the holy oil of Clovis.
YourGrace!
There can be no anointing.
-What areyou talking atxut?
-The holy oil of Clovis ¡s all gone.
Gone?
That’s impossible.
It’s a magic oil. A miraculous oil.
It can never be exhausted.
- Uxkforyourself.
- Problerim?
I just don’t understand.
The oil of ClcMs. It was quite fúlI
the last time I saw it.
- And when was that?
- At the coronation of King Charles Vi.
Thirtyyears ago?
Does ¡t surprise you it’s gone?
But you don’t understand.
It’s no ordinary oil.
It’s a miraculous oil.
It was brought
by a white dove from heaven...
to crown King Clovis
¡n this very cathedral.
-What areyou doing?
- Performing a miracle.
we do anoint thee, Charles Valois...
to be sovereign lord and king
of this great kingdom of France...
charging that ye should defend
the faith of our Mother Holy Church...
as long as ye shall live.
Amen.
Long live the king!
-Jeanne, are you all right?
-Yes, I’m fine.
-Why areyou staring at me?
-You have an arrow ¡nyour leg.
So there ¡s.
But that doesn’t stop you
from climbing!
Well, climb! Go! Go!
Take this arrow out of my leg.
Look ouU
- Becarefùl!
-Jeanne, the men are exhausted.
I know, but so ¡s the enemy.
They’re falling back. Pans ¡s ours.
Jeanne, we are not enough.
So bring up the reinforcements.
Reinforcements? Where?
Right behind us.
Dunois with another 10,000 men.
-Jeanne, look behind you.
- Never lcxk behind. Only ahead.
Do you know how to count?
Of course Ido!
So, bring them up!
Jeanne, that ¡s not
10,000 reinforcements!
That ¡s 1 00...
very loyal
but very tired soldiers!
But where’s Dunois?
And where are the men
the king promised me?
He never sent them!
Don’t you understand?
He doesn’t want this war anymore.
He has his crown now.
That’s all he ever wanted.
But my voices, they promised me.
To hell with yourvoices!
It’s time to face facts!
We have nothing to do here!
None of us!
Not even you.
You donut believe in me anymore?
Jeanne, of course we still
believe in you.
If it were up to me, I’d chase every
gcxidamn Englishman into the ocean.
But it’s not up to us anymore.
It’s up to the king.
You should go home,Jeanne.
We cannot possibly afford to pay
for the size of army she’s demanding.
Girl ¡s crazy.
Her victory at Orléans
was a miracle.
But we can’t wait for a miracle
when we build a future for France.
Pans was a disaster.
God wasn’t with her then.
If GcxJ deserts her,
what do you think we should do?
Why did you betray me? Pans was ours.
All I needed was a few hundred men.
- Why did you take the army you gave me?
- Gave you?
- I wouldn’t quite put it that way.
- So how would you put it?
foryour past efforts...
but now your task ¡s done.
Now is the time for negotiation.
Peace will only be got with the English
by the end of a lance.
Why areyou so blcxxithirsty?
Do you enjoy ¡t?
Diplomacy is far more civilized...
far safer and far cheaper.
I’ve letters here from towns under
siege, where your people are starving...
begging GcxJ on their knees
to help them.
I’m here to answer their prayers.
And you want to stop me?
She belongs to Gcxi
If only she would just go home.
So what am I supposed to do now?
- What do your voices say?
- They haven’t spoken to me ¡n weeks.
Not since the coronation.
No signs, nothing.
Maybe their silence is a sign.
- Maybe it’s a sign to go home.
-No.
It’s not timeyet..
My mission isn’t over yet.
- There’s still more I have to do.
- But how do--
these voices aren’t just really you?
Well, they are me.
That’s how GcxJ speaks to me.
Even you could hear them
¡fyou listened hard enough.
You make ¡t sound so simple.
So even you don’t believe in me anymore.
JeanneI believeinyou
more than anyone.
I just wish I could...
helpyou.
There ¡s one thing you can do
¡fyou want to help me.
Tell me.
We have to stop he,, Your Myesty
If she Rises an army
and attacks the Burgundians...
months of negotiations
will have been in vain.
Jeanne has done so much for us.
I can assure you, the maid has
no greater admirer than myself.
Whatever our personal feelings,
we cannot allow her to conduct..
her own private war.
For the sake of the kingdom, you must
stop her from going to Corn piégne.
I canut stop her.
Well, ¡fyou don’t, I’m sure the
Burgundians would be happy to oblige.
If they capture her at Corn piègne-
No one could blame us.
But ¡t could sound like
we betrayed her.
- No, never.
- Gcxxl heavens, no.
Don’t worry, Charles.
If God ¡s still with her,
she will be victorious.
But her army’s so much smaller.
Then her faith will have to be bigger.
-What areyou doing? Open this gate.
- I can’t risk the safety of my town.
Take my banner!
My Lord.
I can’t believe ¡t.
I must admit,
you have a big imagination.
But maybe not big enough.
Death ¡s much more simple.
After a few months,
¡t gets more interesting.
Then after a year,
¡t finally becomes...
romantic.
Who are you?
You don’t like my face?
Maybeyou’d prefer this one.
Tcx young, maybe.
How about this one?
Better now? But incomplete.
Get thee behind me, Satan.
Wh o a re you to even th ¡ n k you ca n know
the difference between gcxxi and evil?
Are you Gcx?
I’m just a messenger.
He needs me.
How can you imagine that GcxJ,
the creator of heaven and Earth...
the source of all life1..
could possibly need you?
I donut know
You don’t think He’s big enough
to deliver His own messages?
What do you want from me?
Nothing.
I’m here to set you free.
The Duke of Burgundy.
Your king?
Oh, yes, of course.
What’s he gonna pay me with?
Cows? Chickens?
I prefer gold,
and the English have plenty.
I wonder how much they’ll pay to have
the witch of Orléans ¡n their clutches.
The English are so arrogant, they can’t
accept being defeated by a peasant girl.
It has to have been the devil’s work.
Gcxi defeated the English.
And GOEJ allowed you to be caught?
Personally, I don’t believe ¡n God.
I don’t believe in the devil either.
That’s why I’m never disappointed.
To payjeanne’s ransom.
The captains gave what they could,
as well as citizens of Orléans.
That’s very generous of you.
How much?
- Ten thousand gold crowns.
- Ten thousand?
That’s a lot.
Your Grace, I placeyou ¡n charge
of this very delicate negotiation.
Get yourself ready.
You’re leaving.
Pierre Cauchon, bishop of Beauvais.
As you were captured ¡n my diocese, the
duty to conduct the trial falls un me.
Trial?
What trial?
Your tnalJeanne,
on a charge of heresy.
But my king—
Didn’t he pay my ransom?
It seems the English care
more atxut you than the French.
-The English?
-Yes.
They paid your ransom.
Tomorrow you’ll be transferred
to their great castle at Rouen.
Our serene and Christian king, Henry Vi,
king of England and France...
has placed this girl in our hands,
accused of heretical deeds...
to be tried ¡n a matter of faith.
Take the Holy Gospels ¡n your hand...
and swear to tell the truth regarding
anythingyou may be asked.
I don’t know what you will ask me. You
may ask things I won’t want to answer.
You will swear to tell the truth
axut everything you are asked.
I will willingly tell the truth
axut all Earthly things.
But as to my revelations,
I’ve told no one except my king...
Charles Vil, the one and only
king of France.
You must take the oath.
Not even a king would refuse to take
an oath ¡na matter of faith.
I will tellyou all
that I’m allowed to tell you.
But as for the rest..
even ¡fyou threatened
to cut off my head, I won’t tell you.
Begin by telling us your name, assuming
you’re allowed to tell us that much.
My name ¡sJeanne.
My little cross was taken from me.
Mayl have it back?
Show us a little more
ccxperation first.
Where were you txm?
In a village called Domremy.
How old are you?
Nineteen, or thereaLxuts.
Were you baptized?
-Yes.
- Recite our Lord’s Prayer.
Not unless you hear my confession.
Listen to me very carefully.
We are all men of faith...
and we shall earnestly strive for the
salvation of your bcdy and your soul...
¡n the name of our Church who never
closes arms to those who return to her.
But we cannot help you...
unless you submit to our
learned judgment and authority.
Take heed of this
charitable admonition...
for ¡fyou persist
¡n refusing our help...
we shall have no choice but to
abandon you to the secular powers.
And I thinkyou know well enough
the punishment that would await you.
Now...
will you please recite
our Lord’s Prayer?
Not unless you hear my confession.
Be careflul. You aren’t helping yourself
by refusing to submit to our judgment
who claim to be my judges,
you becareftil!
Foryou t one day will be judged.
Guards, take the prisoner away!
- Silence!
— Sorceress!
Silence!
Clear the rm!
In future, we should conduct inquiries
privately, away from public pressure.
Let the English bum her if they want.
Why does it have to involve us?
Because it’s our duty to rt out
heresy wherever we find it.
Father Vincente.
and I won’t be part of it anymore.
I’m willing to be her judge,
but not her executioner.
That’s what I’m trying to ensure.
The verdict comes at the end of
a trial, Cauchon. Not at the beginning.
I am going back to Rome...
to give my rert
to our Holy Father, the Pope.
This is ridiculous. Now I’m the one
who’s on trial and being judged.
-Arrest him.
-What areyou doing?
This is an ecclesiastical court
You’ve no right to do this.
This is English territory.
I have the right to do anything.
Is that clear?
Our Father who art ¡n heaven—
Thy kingdom come—
Forgive us—
Forgive them—
Forgive them, then forgive us.
Forgive them.
Why were you yelling?
What are you doing here?
You can’t stay here! Go away!
Why? Are you waiting for someone else?
- Who?
— My visions.
Your visions.
They’re going tovisityou in here?
Yes. That’s what I pray for.
I want to see that
Doyou mind if I stayon the side here?
- I won’t Lxther you.
-Nol
No you Œn’t! You ŒflPt!
- Or else they won’t come.
- Why won’t they?
Because I have to be alone.
Oh. They won’t come anyway.
- What do you mean, they won’t come?
-Why would they?
Because I’ve always been faithfùl
to God...
and I’ve followed everything
He’s ever said...
and I’ve done everything
He’s everasked me to do.
God asked you to do something?
Yes, lots of things.
You mean, Gcxi said...
‘I needyou,Jeanne’?
But He’s sent me signs.
Signs? What signs?
The wind. The wind.
Wind.
And the clouds. Ringing.
Ringing cloud.
The dance. The dance.
The sword. The sword lying ¡n the field.
That was a sign.
No. That was a sword ¡n a field.
No. No. That was a sign.
No, that was a sword ¡n a field.
It can’t just get there by itself.
It can’t.
A sword just doesn’t get there
by itself.
True. Every event has an infinite
number of causes, so why pick one?
There are many ways a sword
might find itself in a field.
Seems a perfectly valid explanation,
but how about this one?
Then again, there are other
possi bi I ities.
Or even faster.
And that’s without counting
the inexplicable.
Yet from an infinite number of
possibilities you had to pick this one.
You didn’t see what was,Jeanne.
You saw what you wanted to see.
This voice that you say
appears to you...
¡s ¡t an angel or a saint,
or does ¡t come from God?
I won’t tell you any more atxut that.
I’m more afraid of displeasing Him
than not answering you.
You’re afraid of displeasing Gcxi
by telling the truth?
Did Gxi forbid you
to tell the truth?
My revelations were for
the king of France, not for you.
When you saw your king
for the first time...
was there an angel over his head?
If there was one, I did not see it..
Whydidyour king believe ¡nyou
without any prcxf?
Go ask him yourself.
Dinner.
When you were taken prisoner,
did you have a horse?
Yes. A half-steed. Black.
- Who gave you that horse?
- My king.
How many did he give you?
Five steeds...
and a few hackneys.
As much as fora lord.
What an honor.
Did your king give you other wealth
apart from those horses?
What atxut all those dresses
you were given?
Silk dresses, weren’t they?
Yes, I was given a few.
But I never had time to wear them.
Still, pretty wealthy
for a peasant girl, wouldn’t you say?
You kxk pretty wealthy
fora servant of God, wouldn’t you say?
Itriedto.
And didn’t you order the citizens
of Pans to surrender the city...
¡n the name of the King of Heaven?
No. I said, Surrender ¡n the name
of the king of France.
Lcx,k yourself.
I can’t read.
Yes, I forgot
Gcxi sent us an illiterate peasant
to carry out such an important mission.
To take an ignorant girl
to save the kingdom of France?
I leave that answer to God.
Fuck!
Calm down, my lord.
I begyou.
Howcanlwhenl’m made
the laughingstock of the whole court?
You’ve seen how ¡t ¡s.
This girl has a way with people...
but we’re making progress every day.
As long as that bitch remains alive,
our armies refuse to fight. Understand?
They
that God
need pRxf
¡s on their side.
It’s not for us to bum her.
That’s your prerogative.
And it’s your prerogative
to find herguilty!
But we can’t do that
unless she admits to blasphemy.
What are you waiting for?
You’ve got a castle ful of racks,
ropes and pulleys. Torture the bitch!
You’ll never get anything
out of her that way.
And besides...
you must realize that several
of my colleagues are, well, scared.
Scared? Of a girl?
Scared to make a mistake.
Supxse she’s right.
Supxse she has been sent by God
- Who’s side are you on, Cauchon?
- I’m on the side of Holy Mother Church.
Do you have a sword?
- Quite a few.
- Didn’t you also carry a banner?
Which do you prefer?
Your banner oryour sword?
I was 40 times more fond of my banner.
Why? Did ithavesome
particular value or power?
It’s just—
-Asword ¡saweaíxn.
-And?
And so, I prefer my banner.
Why?
To avoid killing anyone.
Are you saying ¡f you’d not
been carrying your banner...
Of course not.
I never killed anyone.
Then perhaps the temptation...
to kill would have been stronger—
t strong, perhaps.
I warned the English to go back home.
We have numerous witnesses
who can confirm...
you were not always
carrying your banner.
Yes, perhaps.
Sometimes you were carrying
just your sword.
Did you use the sword
you held in your hand?
Yes, I used ¡t—
I held itup—
You held up your sword
and flourished ¡t about like this!
I don’t remember.
So, you were on the battlefield
with your sword in your hand...
waving it alxwe your head,
charging against the enemy...
screaming at the enemy,
fighting for vur life..
and you expect us to believe...
that in the middle
ofall this excitement...
you never killed anyone.
No. I neyer killed anyone.
I can’t believe
you can lie like that.
Im not lying. I’m not lying.
Leave me alone. I can’t remember.
-I didn’t kill anyone. I can’t remember.
-Let me help your memory.
I don’t want to hear any more.
Leave me alone. I didn’t kill that man.
Leave me alone!
Stop. Stop. I can’t remember.
The battles were so confusing. I was
only defending myself as best I could.
There was so much dust, smoke and noise.
I was being attacked on all sides.
So maybe perhaps I fought badc
- But ¡t was only to defend myself.
- So your memory’s coming back.
-Yes.
- GTJi1.
Now, you tell me why Gcxi let all those
battles happen ¡n the first place.
He’s so powerful. You said...
He’s the creator of heaven and Earth,
the source of all Iife.
He could easily have stopped
all that bkxxi and misery.
Why didn’t He—
Is He the one who spread
all that blcxxi and misery?
-Is He?
- No. But He could have stopped it.
What, did he get pleasure—
pleasure—
pleasure from watching us killing
each other in His name?
In His name?
In His name. We fought and killed
in His name--
- the King of Heaven.
- Really?
Let all those who love me
flollow me!
Let all who love me
follow mei
Where does GcxJ get mentioned?
Come on,Jeanne.
Be honest.
You fought for yourself.
In your name.
No!
I was defending myself
as best as I could.
Everyone has the right
to defend themselves, don’t they?
Yes, they do!
Should I have let myself get killed?
— Is that it?
- No. You did fine.
I’d even say well done.
As a matter of fact..
most of the ones you killed
probably deserved ¡t, don’tyou think?
I neyer thought killing each other
would bring alxut any ace.
I agree.
Peace will only be got from
the English at the end of a lance.
I don’t agree. Why do you keep
changing your mind all the time?
You. Why—
Why areyou doing this to me?
Do you get pleasure from hurting me?
Pleasure.
That’s a difficult word to define.
When does pain end and pleasure begin?
When did your pleasure begin?
With that sword in your hand?
I neyer txk pleasure...
¡n hurting anyone.
Really?
Set me free. Set me free.
You will be,Jeanne.
Jeanne, myvery dear
friend ¡n ChnsL.
we, your judges and assessors...
desirous of reaching
a true and lawful verdict..
submitted a transcript of your trial
to the University of Pans...
to attain their opinion.
After careful consideration...
the learned scholars
have concluded with us...
that you have committed
many grievous sins.
I ask you now
to listen most carefully...
to their opinion,
as detailed in these articles.
Article One.
You said that by GcxJ’s command you have
continually worn men’s clothes...
and that you have also worn
your hair short..
with nothing to distinguish you from
the soldiers with whom you fought
Don’t abandon me. Please.
Where are You?
Where are You? Please.
Is this what You want?
You want me to...
Wi thouL
being confessed?
Finally, Article 12.
You have said that you are not
willing to submit yourself...
to the judgment of the church militant,
but only to GcxJ.
As to this article,
the scholars say...
that you have no comprehension
of the authority of the Church.
That you have perniciously erred
in the faith of God...
and you are a child of superstition,
a wanderer from the faith...
an invoker of demons, an idolater...
and a heretic.
We once again admonish,
beg and exalt you...
to cast out and recant
your erroneous beliefs...
by signing this recantation.
Please.
wants me to say...
that my visions are evil...
then I do not believe ¡n this Church.
Perform your office.
Wait.
Jeanne, I beg of you, sign.
In GcxJ’s name, don’t you understand?
I’m trying to save you.
I want to be confessed.
And may I—
May I go to Mass?
As often as you like.
Now, for the love of GcxJ, sign.
Sign J eanne,
and you’ll be free of your chains.
Free of the firejeanne.
Thankyou.
Do you know what you just signed?
-l didn’t
- Foryou,
mean to.
He’s a lie.
An illusion.
No,na.
He told me that I would be confessed.
In the end, ¡t was you
who abandoned Him.
- May I have that back, please?
-You have nothing to regret.
Give ¡t back to me!
- Give it back!
- Take her away!
Silence her!
There. She has recanted.
And we accept her repentance...
for the Church never closes her arms
to those who would return to the fold.
Now she’s your martyr, not ours.
Please!
Enough.
Here.
Ifyou want to get dressed,
try these for size.
My lord bishop.
Come to see for yourself.
Well, take a look.
You see?
Dressed as a man again.
Her touching repentance
didn’t last very long, did it?
The Bishop of Senlis was passing by
and was on hand to witness her relapse.
And by what miracle did these clothes
find their way in here?
Nota miracle, mydearCauchon.
An evil spell.
This girl is a witch,
and tomorrow she will bum r it.
Have the stake prepared
¡n the marketplace.
Jeanne, I don’t understand.
Why did you do ¡t?
-Why?
- And you.
Why did you lie?
You promised to have me confessed.
I know. It was the onlyway
to have you saved from the fire.
It’s not my body I want to save.
It’s my soul.
I ask only one thing.
Please, hear my confession.
I can’tJeanne.
I can’t hearyour confession.
I’m very sorry.
You want to confess?
I’m listening.
I’ve committed sins, my Lord.
So many sins.
I saw so many signs.
Many signs.
The ones I wanted to see.
I fought..
out of revenge...
and despair.
that people believe...
they’re allowed to be.
when they’re fighting for...
a cause.
Fora cause.
I was...
proud...
and...
Selfish.
Yes. Cruel.
Cruel.
You thinkyou are ready now?
Good.