Master Li is here!
MAN: Master Li is here!
Shu Lien !
Li Mu Bai is here!
Master Li.
Ll MU BAl: Hello.
How's everything?
WOMAN: Fine.
Please come in.
Li Mu Bai.
lt's been a long time.
lt has.
How's business?
Not bad.
And how are you?
Fine.
Monk Zheng came by
from the Wudang Mountain.
He said you
were practising
deep meditation.
The mountain must be
so peaceful.
l envy you.
My work keeps me so busy
l hardly get a minute's rest.
l broke it off.
l couldn't complete
the training.
Why?
You're a Wudang fighter.
Training is everything.
During my meditation training,
l came to a place of deep
silence.
l was surrounded by light.
Time and space disappeared.
l felt l had come to a place
my master had never told me
about.
You were enlightened.
Far from it.
l didn't feel the bliss
one should feel when
enlightened.
lnstead,
l was surrounded
by an endless sorrow.
lt was more
than l could take.
l couldn't go on.
l failed.
There was something
pulling me back
into the world.
What was it?
Something l can't
seem to let go of.
l see you're
preparing to leave.
We're making
a delivery to Beijing.
Perhaps
l could ask you to deliver
something to Sir Te for me.
The Green Destiny Sword?
You're giving it to Sir Te?
l am.
He has always been
our greatest protector.
l don't understand.
How can you part
with it?
lt's been with
you a long time.
Too many men
have died at
its edge.
lt may look pure
but only because blood
washes easily from its
blade.
You use it
for good cause,
making you worthy of it.
lt's time for me
to leave it behind.
So what will you do then?
Come with me to Beijing.
You can give the sword
to Sir Te in person.
lt'll be just
like old times.
l need to visit
my master's grave.
lt's been many years since
he was murdered by Jade Fox.
l have yet to
avenge his death,
and yet l'm
thinking of quitting.
l must pray for
his forgiveness.
Catch up with me
when you have finished.
l will wait for you
if you come.
Maybe.
Okay, you may pass.
Thanks.
Let's go into the city.
We can rest after we
unload the shipment.
Let's go.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
Thank God
everything is safe.
Much obliged, Miss Yu.
Just doing my job.
Sun Security has been
the best since your
father started it.
You're a credit to
your father's memory.
Thank you.
lt's the truth.
(DRUMS BEATlNG)
This is Li's
personal sword.
A great hero is
worthy of a great weapon.
He is the only one in
the world worthy of it.
lt's too fine a gift.
l cannot accept it.
The sword
has brought Li Mu Bai
as much trouble as glory.
Li wants to leave
these troubles behind.
Take the sword and help him
leave his old way of life.
l see. All right.
l'll act as the sword's
custodian.
Ninth Level Counsel,
Chief Yu has arrived.
l must change.
Yes.
Thank you. You've always been
a great friend to Li and me.
No hurry to leave.
Please feel at home.
You'll stay the night
as my guest.
Now, Shu Lien,
tell me something,
and forgive me
for prying.
But your father was
like a brother to me
and l think of you
as my own daughter.
Please, Sir Te,
what is it?
Li Mu Bai giving up his
sword and his warrior days,
maybe he's hinting
something to you.
l don't know.
Don't be coy.
l've known all along about
your feelings for each other.
Neither of you have
been brave enough
to reveal
your feelings
to each other.
So many years went wasted.
Li Mu Bai and l
aren't cowards.
Maybe it isn't
what you've thought.
(CHUCKLlNG)
When it comes to emotions,
even great heroes can be
idiots.
lf Li Mu Bai
doesn't talk straight
next time you see him,
let me know,
and l'll give
him an earful !
You will stay in this room.
You?
l am
your guest
here today.
This is
Sir Te's study.
You are here to. . .
lt's so crowded out there.
l was looking for a quiet
place.
l'm Sir Te's head servant,
De Lu.
This is
another of
our guests.
lt's heavy for such
a thin piece of metal.
lt's the handle that's heavy.
And that blade is no
ordinary metal.
Still, the sword is the
lightest of all weapons.
You find it heavy
because you're not
used to handling them.
No, l've had a lot
of experience with
weapons.
My father has
security guards
living with us.
They let me play
with their weapons.
This scabbard
is so beautiful.
Beautiful and yet dangerous.
Once you've seen
it tainted with blood,
you'll think otherwise.
lt's 400 years old.
lt's exquisite.
You said this
sword belongs to. . .
My friend Li Mu Bai.
He's given it to
Sir Te as a gift.
Li Mu Bai !
The famous warrior?
l've heard so much about him.
Why would he give
his sword to Sir Te?
lt's a long story.
You must be
a sword fighter, too.
Yes, but l prefer
the machete.
This sword fits
Li Mu Bai perfectly.
Really.
lt must be
exciting to
be a fighter.
Fighters have rules, too.
Friendship, trust, integrity.
Always keep your promise.
Without rules,
we wouldn't survive long.
l've read all
about people
like you.
Roaming wild,
beating up anyone
who gets in your way!
Writers have to
write like that
to sell books.
You're just like the
characters in the stories.
Sure, no place to bathe
for days, sleeping on
flea-infested beds.
They tell you
all about that
in those books?
You know what l mean.
l'm getting married soon,
but l haven't lived the
life l want.
l've heard of
your engagement.
Congratulations.
lt's the most important step
in a woman's life, isn't it?
You are not married,
are you?
What do you think?
No. You couldn't roam
around freely if you were.
l admit you're
probably right.
SlR TE: Chief Yu,
take a look.
2 feet 9 inches long,
1 . 1 inch wide.
The handle
is 1 inch long,
2.6 inches wide,
0.7 inch thick,
each side is 1 .5 inches.
With seven rubies
missing from the hilt.
You can tell from
the design that it was made
during the Qin Wu era.
(SWORD CLANGlNG)
Engraved
with a technique lost
during the Han Dynasty.
Your knowledge
is remarkable.
A sword by itself
rules nothing.
lt comes
alive only through
skilful manipulation.
l see your point.
Please continue, Sir Te.
The inner city in
Beijing is not a problem.
With royalty and
officials everywhere
the Royal Guard
keep security tight.
But the outer city
is hard to govern.
lt's full of
complex characters.
Proceed with caution
in your quest for
law and order.
Don't depend
only on the court.
Keep some contacts
in the Jiang Hu
underworld.
lt can ensure
your position.
Be strong yet supple.
This is the way to rule.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Governess.
Let me do it.
Please sit.
l've made
a pair of silk pyjamas.
Want to change into them?
Leave them there.
l heard you met
Yu Shu Lien today.
You know her?
Your mother
would not want you
consorting with her kind.
l'll socialise with
whomever l please.
Don't invite danger
into your father's house.
l'm tired now!
Go to bed then.
You've grown up and
will get married soon.
God knows what
the future will bring.
lt'll be just the same.
Enough, l'm tired.
lt's autumn now.
l'll shut the
windows for you.
MAN: Chilly, eh?
Good evening, Bo.
Thief!
(GRUNTlNG)
Someone help!
Catch the thief!
He's on the rooftop!
(MEN CHATTERlNG)
The sword's been stolen !
Someone help!
He's on the roof!
Stop, thief!
(MEN SHOUTlNG)
Catch him !
MAY: Avenge my mother!
(YELLlNG)
What are you standing
here for? Go get him !
Return the sword,
and l'll let you go.
You've been
trained at Wudang?
We are street performers.
You're wrong.
We're just
practising
the stunts.
Let's go.
Practising? Who are
you trying to fool?
Where did they go?
Chief Yu's house.
(GRUNTlNG)
SHU LlEN: Get down here!
Get down.
Give me the sword.
Sir Te awaits you
in the great hall.
BO: l didn't get
the sword back.
But l'm sure the thief's
connected to the Yus.
How dare you !
But l saw. . .
Enough ! Get out!
Has Chief Yu
ever seen the sword?
Yes, though l doubt
he's involved in this.
But the sword is somewhere
in his compound.
Then someone's
out to frame him.
We should get word
to Li Mu Bai about this.
GOVERNESS:
Watch your step.
What happened?
What is it?
Someone's put fliers up.
Go away.
(MEN CHATTERlNG)
Let me see.
Someone's after Jade Fox.
Preposterous,
looking for her here!
Best spear fighting
in the world !
The Yang School
of Spear Fighting !
(BELL RlNGlNG)
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(MAN CHANTlNG)
Where did they go?
l really don't know.
l saw them
couple of days ago.
Probably gone by now.
Miss, there's
a Miss Yu here
asking to see you.
Our Lady is
busy right now.
l will tell her then.
Show her in.
Yes.
This spells trouble.
l have a guest now.
This way please, Miss Yu.
l've missed you !
Missed me? How so?
l have nothing to do.
You're
practising
calligraphy.
l'll write your name.
Just for fun.
l never noticed that my name
looks like the word for sword.
You write gracefully.
Calligraphy is so
similar to fencing.
Maybe it is.
l wouldn't know.
Please.
Thank you for seeing me.
l hear your
wedding day
is near.
You must be overwhelmed
with the preparations.
l'm hardly
doing a thing.
The less l think
of it, the better.
My parents are
arranging everything,
including the groom.
Mother says the Gous
are a very powerful
family.
My marrying into this family
will give my dad's career
a big boost.
lt's
a great fortune to marry
into such a noble family.
ls it? Actually,
l like the great
heroes in the books
just like you
and Li Mu Bai.
Marriage is
a good thing.
lf only l could be
free to live my
own life,
to choose who l love
and love him in my
own way.
That's real happiness.
Think so?
Let me tell you a story.
About you and Li Mu Bai?
Yes. l was once engaged
to be married when l
was young.
Really?
His name was Meng Si Zhao.
He was a brother-by-oath
to Li Mu Bai.
One day,
while defending
Li Mu Bai in battle
he was killed by
another man's sword.
After Meng's sacrifice,
Li and l went through
a lot together.
Our feelings
for each other
grew stronger.
But we decided to honour
my engagement to Meng.
The freedom
you talk about,
l too desire it,
but l've never tasted it.
lt's not your fault,
or Li Mu Bai's.
Too bad for
Meng, but that's just
the way things turn out.
As a woman,
l still must
abide by tradition
even if l'm not
an aristocrat like you.
Don't distance us. From
now on, let's be sisters.
All right. As a sister,
l hope you find real
happiness.
MADAME YU: Miles
and miles of nothing.
Can't your father
get an appointment
closer to civilisation?
This place!
Jen, are you
listening to me?
Let's go!
(GROANlNG)
Who are you?
Dad !
Hold it! l'm a friend !
l don't care
about your sword.
Why are you
spying on the Yus?
l'm looking for someone.
Jade Fox.
l'm a police inspector
from the Shaan Xi,
Gen Su district.
This Jade Fox is
a master criminal.
l hear she
infiltrated the Yus.
She must
have come with them
when he transferred here.
But l cannot just go in
and catch her there.
l have to lure her out.
This Jade Fox is a woman?
You bet.
Then leave her to me.
Don't worry.
Thank you, but l doubt
you can handle her.
My wife used to be
quite a martial artist.
Jade Fox killed her.
lt's both an official
and a personal matter
to me.
Meatballs are ready!
l'm more than
ready for them.
Wait, dad gets first dip!
Hey!
They are gone.
What does it say?
We'll settle this at midnight
tonight on Cemetery Hill.
Good ! The Fox is
out of her hole.
Please.
Shu Lien,
look who's here.
Sir Te thinks
it's not appropriate
to cast doubt on Chief Yu.
But there is something up
in the Yu household.
l'm investigating.
What have you found?
Jade Fox?
lmpossible!
You'd
always suspected
she'd fled out west.
She has the nerve
to come to Beijing.
ls there any place safer than
under the nose of Chief Yu?
l shall avenge my
master's death after all.
But be careful, Li Mu Bai.
Sir Te requires discretion.
Official business is already
difficult to resolve,
it'd be a bigger mess
with your personal matters
involved.
And l don't know, this
flyer may not be reliable.
lt could be
some sort of trap.
Did you see who posted it?
No.
lt says Fox is
hiding at Yu's.
Sir Te says the night of
the theft there was a brawl
in front of Yu's.
Were you involved?
No, that was Bo,
Sir Te's man.
Bo followed the
thief to the Yus.
Have you
cross-examined him yet?
Bo? No, not yet. . .
But you've had your men
stake out Yu's compound?
No, l'd already
sent them back.
You can blame me
for losing the sword
but trust me,
l'll get it back soon
using my own methods.
That's not what l meant.
l don't care about the
sword.
How can you say that?
Didn't you come back
here for it?
l didn't know it was
stolen until l got here.
Then, why did you come?
Well, we had talked. . .
Pardon my intrusion.
Master Li, your room
is ready.
Thank you.
Please, lead the way.
BO: This Fox doesn't care
much for punctuality.
There's no sign of her.
BO: Enough !
Don't pretend any more.
Tsai ! You old scoundrel !
You won't leave me alone.
Payback time!
Yeah, old lady?
Watch your mouth !
lf you surrender now,
you'll suffer less.
lf you resist,
you're dead today.
Dad ! Let me avenge
my mother's death.
You'll end up like her,
you little whore!
You old fox!
(SCREAMlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
(GROANS)
MAY: Dad !
(SCREAMlNG)
TSAl: You old fox,
you ruined my life.
You won't get away with it.
Watch out for
her acupressure!
TSAl: Sue!
Tsai, you dog !
You even have hidden hands!
MAY: Dad, are you okay?
TSAl: l'm fine.
Wudang should have
gotten rid of you
long ago.
lt's been a long time,
Jade Fox!
You probably
don't remember me.
But you remember my master.
You infiltrated my clan
while l was away.
You poisoned my master
and stole the secret manual.
Now it's time for you to pay!
Your master
underestimated us women.
He wouldn't
teach me even after
he'd slept with me.
He deserved to die
by a woman's hands!
(SCREAMlNG)
You stole
the top secrets of
Wudang's martial arts.
But you've mastered only
the basic moves in the
past ten years.
For you to die under
Wudang's sword today
is no disgrace!
My disciple!
Fight with me!
We'll kill them all !
Fox has a disciple!
l've got to get rid of Tsai !
Go.
Who are you?
Why is the
Green Destiny Sword
in your possession?
lt's none of your business.
My name is Li Mu Bai.
The Green Destiny
Sword is mine.
Jade Fox can't
be your master.
Where did you learn
this "Xuan Piu" move?
Piece of cake.
Ll MU BAl:
Who is your master?
(GROANS)
MAY: Dad !
Let's go.
l'll kill them
once and for all.
Hurry up.
We can't stay here.
Let's go!
MAY: Dad !
Dad !
Dad.
This is Tsai?
My father.
Police lnspector from Shaan.
Homicide must be
reported to Chief Yu.
ln addition,
the victim is an officer.
You believe
the killer is hiding
out in this compound?
l'd put my life on it, sir.
Come with me.
This needs to be
resolved, and quickly.
l'll get into the Yu
household and get her.
l'll ferret
out this Fox and
her gang in no time.
Too dangerous.
Yu is a court official
and in charge of security.
This could ruin his
reputation and career.
lt might also get
Sir Te in trouble.
This calls for
the utmost delicacy.
Sir Te, can you find some
excuse to invite Mrs and
Miss Yu over?
What do you have in mind?
The best way to trap a fox
is through her cubs.
Oh, my!
Mrs Te is spoiling us
with all these gifts.
She is being
so considerate
to our daughter.
l'm sorry she's not
feeling well enough
to entertain you today.
l heard Sir Te
has lost something.
And now Mrs Te
is not feeling well.
We know who stole
the missing item.
lf the thief returns it
l'm sure Sir Te will pursue
the matter no further.
That's good.
lt's a real annoyance
to have servants who
steal.
Sir Te knows that even
well-meaning people
sometimes make mistakes.
Some mistakes can ruin not
only themselves but their
entire family as well.
But don't be too lenient.
Sure. For example, no mercy
will be shown to the murderer
who just turned up in Beijing.
MADAME YU: A murderer?
Yes, the very killer of
Li Mu Bai's own master.
Last night she
killed a policeman who had
tracked her for many years.
MADAME YU:
A female criminal !
Now that's news!
You say she killed
a policeman?
Yes, from the west.
He went undercover
as a street performer,
and followed her here.
l'm no detective, but maybe
the murderer and thief are
the same.
l doubt that.
This particular thief
is very unusual.
And most likely smarter
than a mere killer.
Greetings, Sir Te.
Hello, Mrs Yu.
Let me introduce Li Mu Bai,
the renowned swordsman.
lt's a pleasure
to meet you,
Mrs Yu, Ms Yu.
Ms Yu is
getting married soon.
Congratulations.
(DOOR CREAKlNG)
Why don't you come in?
l'm standing guard.
Come in. lt's cold.
Come in.
We don't have to fear
Jade Fox if we're together.
Ll MU BAl: lsn't it
a little late to be
out?
You can give
the sword to me.
l'll do as l please.
(GROANS)
Where's your master?
None of your business!
Ll MU BAl:
Had enough flying?
(PANTlNG)
You've got potential.
But you've misunderstood
Wudang's secret manual
quite a bit.
(SCOFFS)
You need a real master.
A master like you?
lt's a meaningless
title.
Ll MU BAl: You're right,
it's all meaningless.
School is meaningless,
the secret manual is
meaningless
even this sword.
lt is just a state of mind.
Don't talk like a monk
just because you're in
a temple. Just fight!
Then tell me
where Jade Fox is!
Move!
True strength is
light as a feather.
(SCREAMS)
No assistance,
no growth.
No reaction,
no explanation.
No control, no desire.
Give yourself up
and find yourself again.
Here's a lesson
for you on life.
Go ahead.
Why should l?
You need practise.
Learn to defeat
movement with stillness.
That way you'll be worthy
of the Green Destiny.
Why do you want
to teach me?
l've always wanted
a disciple worthy of
the Wudang secrets.
Aren't you afraid
that l'd kill you
once l mastered it?
That's a risk l'm willing
to take as your teacher.
Deep down you're good. Even
Jade Fox hasn't been able
to corrupt you.
Wudang is a whorehouse!
Keep your lessons to
yourself!
You're home late,
or should l say
early?
Why are you still here?
You've killed a policeman !
You'll bring ruin
on my whole family.
They wouldn't have tracked
me here if you hadn't
stolen the sword.
You're not
a little girl any more.
You thought
this would be fun?
l'm in this,
and you're in too.
Come with me, Jen.
You don't want
to waste your life
as the wife of some
pompous bureaucrat.
As master and disciple,
we will rule.
l'll never
live as a thief.
You're already
the most wanted thief!
That was just for fun.
Why would l leave,
and where?
Wherever.
Wherever we want.
We'd get rid of
anyone in our way.
Even your father.
Shut up!
That's the underworld
fighter lifestyle.
Kill or be killed.
Exciting, isn't it?
l've fulfilled my
obligations to you.
No, l have.
To have you as my disciple
is the thing in my life
l'm most proud of.
You think you've been
teaching me all these
years from the manual?
Thank goodness
you're illiterate.
l studied the illustrations,
and you studied the words.
You hid the
details from me?
You wouldn't
have understood it even
if you knew how to read.
You know you've gone
as far as you will go.
l hid my skills from you
because l was afraid you
might get hurt.
lf it weren't for
seeing you fight
with Li Mu Bai,
l'd still be ignorant
of all you've hidden
from me.
Governess.
l started
learning from you in
secret when l was 1 0.
You enchanted
me with the dream of
the Jiang Hu underworld.
But once l realised
l could exceed you,
you can't imagine
how frightened l was!
l had no
one to guide me,
no one to follow,
no one to learn from.
There will be more
frightening things
ahead.
(SWORD CLANGlNG)
Are you happy now
that the sword is
back?
l admit, getting it
back made me realise
how much l missed it.
But it's not your
sword any more, is it?
You gave it to Sir Te.
True. But l must borrow
it for one last job.
Jade Fox will
die on its edge.
Did you know
what you were hiding when
you covered for that girl?
My job was
to recover the sword
without embarrassing anyone.
l wasn't about to ruin
her life, or her father.
You did your job well.
The sword is back.
But. . .this girl.
l saw her last night.
l knew you'd
be suspicious.
She needs controlling.
She needs real
direction and
training.
She's an aristocrat's
daughter, she's not
one of us.
lt will all
be over soon.
You'll kill Fox
and she'll marry.
That's not her.
She should become
a Wudang disciple.
But Wudang doesn't
accept women.
For her, perhaps
they could make
an exception.
lf not, left to her own,
l'm afraid she'll become
a poisonous dragon.
lt's not our affair.
Even if Wudang accepts her,
her husband might object.
l thought by
giving away the sword,
l could escape
the Jiang Hu world.
But the cycle of
bloodshed continues.
l had hoped so, too.
l wish
there were something
l could do to help you.
Just be patient
with me, Shu Lien.
(CLATTERlNG)
Freeze!
Lo!
Jen !
You shouldn't have come.
With all the traffic on
your rooftop these days
it took me a while
to get in here.
l can't
wait any longer, Jen.
l was wrong to let you go.
Come with me,
back to the desert.
You'll be happy there.
You can do
whatever you want.
JEN YU: You have been
looking for me all
this time?
Jen, stop playing with it.
l won't break it.
Charge!
(ALL SCREAMlNG)
Stop!
lt's Dark Cloud !
Dark Cloud is coming !
(ALL YELLlNG)
Protect the ladies.
Lower the shade,
don't be seen !
Don't be afraid, Miss.
(HORSES NElGHlNG)
(SHOUTlNG)
Don't touch the women !
Come!
Come get your comb.
(GROANlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
(PANTlNG)
LO: Hey!
Your mother is fine.
Hurry back to your
mother.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(MEN CLAMOURlNG)
LO: Hey!
She's mine!
Leave her to me!
(HORSES NElGHlNG)
LO: Come get your comb.
JEN YU:
Give me back my comb!
LO: Take a break.
JEN YU:
Give me back my comb!
You're tired.
You need rest.
Your horse needs water.
There's a spring up here.
(LO LAUGHlNG)
Well, there was
when l last visited.
Your name?
My name is Lo.
The Hans call
me Dark Cloud.
l'm not that tall
or that big, but l'm
quick as lightning.
Here.
(BOTH GRUNTlNG)
Give me my comb.
Go to hell.
lf you like that,
l can make you a bow.
Great for
hunting pheasants.
They're delicious.
You need to eat something.
Understand?
That way, you'll have
the strength to fight.
Understand?
You'll slowly regain your
strength. Don't rush.
(HUMMlNG)
(COUGHlNG)
You have a bad temper.
lt's much better this way.
You coward !
Still in a bad mood?
But you're speaking.
What's your name?
(SPlTTlNG)
l didn't think the
Hans had names
like that.
(SOBBlNG)
Relax. lf l wanted to
do what you think l want to
do, l'd have done it already.
You must be
dying for a bath.
The water source is far,
and difficult to get to.
l managed to bring
back some fresh water.
You can
wear my clothes
when you are done.
They're clean.
LO: Don't worry.
l'll sing a song,
so you'll know
where l am.
After the bath, you
will calm down a little.
But promise me,
no more rocks
on the head.
(SlNGlNG)
All this trouble,
just for a comb?
lt's mine.
And it's worth a lot to me.
But to a barbarian like
you, it's nothing.
Not true. l can use it to
pick fleas from my horse.
By the way,
l'm a real Manchurian.
l'm sorry,
l guessed wrong.
l thought
you were a Han.
Give me back my comb.
l don't take
orders from anyone.
Give it to me.
(GRUNTlNG)
LO: One night,
when l was a boy
l saw
a thousand stars
fall out of the sky.
l remember thinking,
where did they all go?
l'm an orphan.
l used to look
for stars alone.
Maybe if l rode
to the other end of
the desert, l'd find them.
l've been riding in
the desert ever since.
And that
little boy became
a fearsome bandit.
Couldn't find the stars,
so now he steals my comb.
Out there, you're always
fighting for survival.
You have to gang up
just to stand a chance.
Slowly, your gang
becomes your family.
All that
Dark Cloud stuff
is just propaganda
but it does
make my life easier.
So you are still
the little boy at heart
looking for fallen stars.
l am a man. And l've found
the brightest star of them
all.
Your father's men
are looking for you.
(MEN CHATTERlNG)
They're still out there,
circling closer.
Let them look.
They'll keep looking.
lt's trouble for me.
Don't even think
of sending me back.
lt's up to you.
You might
get tired of this
and start
missing your family.
lf we had a daughter,
we'd look for her, too.
She'd miss us, too.
Jen, l want you
to be mine forever.
What if l make
my mark on the world,
earn your parents' respect?
We have a legend.
Anyone who dares to
jump from the mountain,
God will fulfil
a wish of his.
A long time ago, a man's
parents were ill, so he
jumped.
He didn't die,
wasn't even wounded.
He just floated away,
far away, never to return.
He knew
his wish had come true.
lf you believe in it,
it will happen.
l've asked old people,
they say,
"A sincere heart will make
your dreams come true."
Keep it safe.
And return it to me
when we are together again.
l will.
lf you don't return it to me,
l will have to chase you down.
And next time,
l won't go easy on you.
Wherever l went, they
always recognised me.
l really tried.
l heard
you came to Beijing.
l was afraid l'd
never see you again.
So l came.
l can't let you
get married like that.
Go back.
Jen.
Don't ever come back.
This is it?
Yes.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
MAlD: We heard noises.
ls everything all right?
Fine. lt was just a cat.
You think Jade Fox
will show up?
She must be nearby.
But l doubt
she'll show herself.
We'll keep our eyes open.
She'll come for the girl
sooner or later.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
Jen !
(PEOPLE SCREAMlNG)
Go back to
Xin Jiang with me.
(HORSE NElGHlNG)
LO: Let go of me.
Jen, you can't
marry someone else.
You're mine.
Go back to Xin Jiang
with me.
Jen, come back to
Xin Jiang with me.
Tell me.
Where is Jade Fox?
Come with me. Hurry.
SHU LlEN: You really
thought she'd give it all up
and go back west with you?
She's mine.
Ll MU BAl:
Whether she's yours or not
you will
be no good to her dead.
With Gou and Yu hunting you,
it won't be long until
you're in their hands.
l don't care any more.
lf you truly loved her,
you wouldn't say that.
Don't you want
to see her again?
l'll write
an introduction for you.
Take it to Wudang Mountain.
Wait there
for news from me.
Okay.
When will this end?
They take it, put it back,
and take it again.
My place is no better
than a warehouse.
Come in.
Speak.
Jen Yu's run away.
The groom found
her missing.
Chief Yu requests
your assistance
since you
know the Jiang Hu
underworld so well.
He wants to find her
and keep her from harm.
Sir Te, leave this to us.
Don't worry.
What can l serve you?
This cup is dirty.
Hi there.
May l ask your name?
Long.
lt's young
master Long.
My apologies!
l'm lron Eagle Sung.
This is
my fellow brother,
Flying Cougar Li Yun.
What brings you to Huai An
and where are you headed,
Master Long?
Anywhere there's action.
ln that case,
perhaps we could
be of assistance.
Don't bother.
You don't seem to
be getting our drift.
So what if l don't?
We have
ways of dealing with
people who don't get it.
(CLATTERlNG)
Are you related
to Li Mu Bai?
He's my defeated foe.
SHU LlEN: Some tea.
Shu Lien.
There's no eternity
to the things we can touch.
My master used to say,
"There's nothing
we can hold onto
in this world.
"Only by letting go can we
finally possess what is real."
Even to an old
Taoist like you, not
everything is an illusion.
When you were holding
my hand just now,
wasn't that real?
Your hand is
cold and callused
from practising machetes.
All these years,
and l've never had
the courage to touch it.
Crouching tigers
and hidden dragons
are in the underworld
but so are human feelings.
Swords and knives
harbour unknown perils,
but so do human relationships.
l gave away the Green Destiny
with sincerity.
But it brought us
more troubles.
Repressing your feelings
will only make them stronger.
l can't repress my desire.
l want to be with you.
Just sitting like this
gives me a sense of peace.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(MUSlC PLAYlNG)
Please follow me.
l want a clean room.
There are plenty of rooms.
What would you like to eat?
Some steamed cod, fried ribs,
meatballs, not too big,
with little starch !
And cabbage soup
with shark fins, plus
a bottle of warm rose wine.
l have to
order them from
a bigger restaurant.
Hurry then.
Yes.
GANGSTER 1 : lt's him.
l am lron Arm Mi.
l heard
a true master has arrived.
l have come to seek a lesson.
You asked for it!
(MEN MURMURlNG)
(YELLlNG)
What kind of
lron Arm are you?
(SCREAMlNG)
(PEOPLE CLAMOURlNG)
That's
amazing technique!
l am Flying Machete.
Are you related
to Southern Crane?
Southern Duck? l don't
eat anything with two feet.
Who could remember
such lengthy names?
You !
lf Li Mu Bai is
your defeated foe,
why don't you
know his master?
Who are you?
l'm Phoenix Mountain Gou.
Gou? l hate that name.
l feel like throwing up
when l hear that name.
Too bad you're named Gou !
You'll be the first to
taste my sword today.
Hold it!
Don't you know Monk Jing?
A monk eating meat and
not reading scriptures?
You need a lesson, too.
Who the hell are you?
l am. . .
GANGSTER 2:
Be careful of her sword !
. . .the invincible
Sword Goddess
with the Green Destiny
that has no equal
be it Li or
Southern Eagle.
Lower your head
and ask for mercy!
l'm the dragon
from the desert
with no trace to be
discovered in my wake.
Today l fly over
Eh-Mei Mountain,
tomorrow, l'll uproot
the last dregs of Wudang !
We politely asked
for a friendly match,
but she showed no respect
and started to reproach
and attack us.
My friends offered
to come by and teach
her a lesson.
Her sword is
just too powerful.
l've travelled far and wide,
but l've never met anyone
that uncivilised.
She kept
accusing me of being
the brother of Gou Jun Pei.
Who is this guy Gou,
anyway?
Her husband.
(PEOPLE MURMURlNG)
Sun Security is nearby.
Why don't you go home and
see how things are going?
What about you?
l'll look around
and catch up later.
Not a bad idea. Let's stay
at Sun Security tonight.
Get a good
night's sleep.
Yes.
You are back.
You're back, Master!
Hello guys.
How's home?
Things are fine.
You've been gone a while.
Something came up.
l leave tomorrow.
Wei, your wife was due?
Yes, a baby girl.
A girl? Good.
l'd be happy
if she grows
up like you.
Mrs Wu.
You're back!
How's the arm?
Still sore?
Much better.
l've been worried about you.
Mrs Wu, Li Mu Bai is
coming to stay the night.
Really? l'll go and
tidy up the room then.
Sister Yu !
You came to find me.
Let's find you some
proper clothes.
l'm just borrowing them.
l'm not moving in.
You get around pretty well.
l don't think you need my
clothes.
l just happened to be around.
l wanted to see how you're
doing.
Sister. . .
Now, now. With all
the trouble you've
caused,
now you know what
Jiang Hu life is
really like.
You came here,
that means you think
of me as your sister.
lf so, let me give you
some sisterly advice.
You don't have to marry,
you can't just leave
your parents.
But they're the ones
who forced me to get
married.
Go back
to your parents first.
Then you can decide about Lo.
You know about Lo?
He really loves you.
Come back to
Beijing with me.
We'll figure
a way out for you.
Where is he now?
Li Mu Bai has
made arrangements.
Li Mu Bai?
He sent him to
Wudang Mountain.
So, you're all working
together to set me up.
Shut up!
How dare you accuse us!
From the beginning, l knew
you stole the Green Destiny!
l've done nothing but
protect you and your
family.
And you've repaid me
with nothing but contempt.
Li Mu Bai spared you,
and all you do is
insult him.
All we hoped
for was a little peace,
and you've ruined it for us!
You're no sister of mine!
l don't give a damn.
Friendship is
not real anyway.
But l wonder, how long
could you last as my enemy?
Put the sword down.
(MEN YELLlNG)
Jen !
Everyone out.
Shut the doors.
Fine.
No more friendship.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Don't touch it.
That's Li Mu Bai's sword.
Come and get it if you can.
You just rely on
the Green Destiny
to do your fighting.
Don't blame the weapon
if you can't fight me.
(CLATTERlNG)
Go ahead. Take your pick.
l'll wait.
Go ahead.
Give me the sword.
Take it!
Ll MU BAl: Stop!
You are not worthy
of this sword.
Not another lecture!
On guard !
Stop yourself before l do.
Now the sword
will settle it.
l didn't force you
at the monastery because
l wanted to see the real you.
What do you know about
seeing a true heart?
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
Why can't you
leave me alone?
l'll say it again,
let me teach you.
Okay, if you can take back
the sword in three moves
l will go with you.
Give it back.
Greet your master.
You wish.
Then the sword is useless.
(THUNDER RUMBLlNG)
lt's only
a matter of time before
those guys get their revenge.
Your parents
value their reputation.
They'll never take you back.
What good's a home?
You've gone so far.
Now we can go all
the way together.
You'll always be my Lady.
After all, happiness is
the most important thing
in life, isn't it?
We'll be our
own masters at last.
All we have left is each
other, isn't that so?
Now lie down and rest.
Crazy girl like that,
you should have killed her.
l didn't have
the heart to do it.
Maybe Li Mu Bai
can do it.
ls it me or
the sword you want?
You've been drugged.
Where's Jade Fox?
What's going on?
Jade Fox drugged her.
How did you get here?
We followed Jade Fox.
Watch out!
(SCREAMlNG)
Governess!
This is the end of the road.
For you too.
A poisoned needle!
You deserve to die
but l was really
aiming at Jen.
Ten years l sacrificed
but you deceived me.
You hid the book's true
meaning. l never improved
but your progress
was limitless.
You know what poison is?
An eight-year-old girl
who's full of deceit!
That's poison !
Jen !
My only love,
my only enemy!
You can't die! Tell us,
what poison did you use?
What poison?
You can't die,
tell us the antidote!
You can't let him die!
Li Mu Bai can't die!
JEN YU: lt's the
Purple Yin Poison.
What?
lt goes straight
to the heart.
My blood
will stop flowing
within two hours.
lt's the same poison
that killed my master.
There's no antidote.
There must be an antidote!
Every living thing
has its antithesis.
And not this?
There is.
Fox taught it to me.
The recipe isn't complicated,
but the ingredients are hard
to find. lt takes time.
Please, trust me.
As you have helped me,
let me help him.
All right. Hurry up.
Maybe l can hold
on for two hours.
Ride
my horse to headquarters.
They have the ingredients.
Give this to Mrs Wu.
She'll help you. Hurry!
Save your breath.
Guard your energy.
l'll be back.
MAN: Who is this?
(PEOPLE YELLlNG)
Mrs Wu !
Where's Mrs Wu?
Stop it!
Yu gave me this
and told me to
come to you.
Let her come in !
Mu Bai, hold on.
Give me some hope.
Shu Lien.
(SHUSHlNG)
Don't waste your breath.
My life is departing.
l've only one breath left.
Use your last bit of
strength to meditate.
Free yourself
from this world as
you've been taught.
Let your soul
rise to eternity
with your last breath.
Don't waste it on me.
l've already wasted
my whole life.
l want to tell you
with my remaining
strength
that l love you.
l always have.
l'll drift next to you
everyday as a ghost
just to be with you.
Even if l was banished
to the darkest place,
my love
will keep me from
being a lonely spirit.
(WHlMPERlNG)
He's gone?
Bo,
please take this sword
back to Sir Te's.
You may go to
Wudang Mountain.
Lo awaits you there.
Promise me whatever path
you decide to take in
this life,
be true to yourself.
Jen !
(CHATTERlNG)
Jen.
Remember the story
you told me in the desert?
Have faith, then the
dreams will come true.
Make a wish, Lo.
l wish that we'll
be in the desert,
together again.